Waleed Shendy

Address: Madinaty City, Cairo, Egypt Mobile: +201005646939 Email: eng shendy78@hotmail.com

Profile Summary

Experienced Purchase & Logistics Manager with over 15 years of outstanding performance and rich experience within Oil and Gas / Construction Industry. Skilled with sound knowledge of various purchase disciplines such as Planning, Cost Control, inventory Control & Logistics. Displayed caliber in managing projects of various types, sizes and complexities. Able to work well as an individual and as part of a team. Possess excellent analytical, organizing, decision making, coordination and time management skills.

Career Objective

Aspiring to be and Ambitious business professional dedicated towards managing overall purchasing operations, including stock level management and maintenance. Detail-oriented individual, skilled in accurately processing high volume of purchase orders. A Competent team player with ability to establish and maintain positive relationships with various stakeholders. Creative thinker, constantly focusing on bottom-line results while contributing enthusiastically to procurement cost-reduction initiatives. Demonstrating multi-tasking skills while prioritizing work assignments. Seeking opportunity to achieve mutual growth and manage varied and challenging assignments in competitive and dynamic work environments.

Core Competencies

- Supply Chain Management
- Expediting Skills
- Logistics
- Vendor Management
- Negotiation Skills
- Cost Reduction
- Documentation
- Process Enhancement
- Presentation Skills
- Team Management

Professional Work Experience

Procurement Manager at Taga Arabia (Taga Gas)

(February, 2017– Present)

Client: Egyptian Holding Gas (E-Gas)

Location: Maadi, Cairo, Egypt.

Scope:

- Engineering, Procurement, Construction and Operation all over projects in Egypt.
- Total Budget Value: 2 Billion Egyptian pounds per Year.

Procurement Manager at Talaat Moustafa Group

(Madinaty for the Projects Management)

(August, 2016 – February 2017)#

Madinaty City Hall

- Client: Talaat Moustafa Holding Group
- Location : Madinaty, New Cairo, Suez Road, Cairo, Egypt
- Scope: Procurement, Construction and Operation of over an area of 3,200 hectares (8,000 acres), with around 3900 residential units.
- Total Budget Value: 60 Billion Egyptian pounds.





Procurement Manager at Saudi Binladin Group (Arch. & Construction Div.)

(Feb, 2014 - July, 2017)

Prophet Mosque Expansion Project

- Client: Saudi Ministry of Finance
- Location : Al-Madina Al Monawarh Saudi Arabia
- Scope: Engineering, Procurement and Construction of Main Prayer Hall and Piazza to accommodate more than 1.6 Million worshippers with a total area of 400,500 sq. meter
- Value: 26 Billion Saudi Ryals.



محموعة بن لادن السعودية SAUDI BINLADIN GROUP

ARCHITECTURE & BUILDING CONSTRUCTION DIVISION

Procurement Manager at Eni Iraq B.V

(Sep, 2012 – Feb 2014)

Provision Electrical / Instrumentation Maintenance Services Project:

- Client: South Oil Company / Basrah
- Scope: Execution of the Electrical and Instrumentation Maintenance Works on all the degassing station, peripheral stations, and in the well head surface areas / Procurement of relevant consumables, spare parts.
- Value: \$ 27 M

Provision of Mechanical Maintenance Services Project:

- Client: South Oil Company / Basrah
- Scope: Execution of the Mechanical Maintenance Works on all the degassing station, peripheral stations, and in the well head surface areas / Procurement of relevant consumables, spare parts.
- Value: \$ 25 M

Provision Generators Maintenance Services Project:

- Client: South Oil Company / Basrah
- Scope: Personnel, Equipment and Spare parts for preventive maintenance and overhauling of ESP generators at Zubair Field (52 well).
- Value: \$ 12 M

Provision of inspection, refurbishment, repair & commissioning of oil tank Project:

- Client: South Oil Company / Basrah
- Scope: Tanks inspection, repair, alteration and reconstruction as per API standards 653 in order to restore the proper tank functionality till the commissioning and start up. Including bottom plate's replacement.
- Value: \$ 19 M

Procurement Section Head at Egyptian Maintenance Company J.V between Egyptian General Petroleum Corporation and Norwegian Vetco Aibel

(2002 - Sep 2012)

1 - Onshore

1.1 LNG Plant Global Maintenance:

• Client: SEGAS

• Location : Damietta Port

1.2 Midor Refineries Global Maintenance:

• Client : Midor

• Location : Alexandria

1.3 Hapy Onshore & Offshore Global Maintenance:

• Client: PHPC

Location : Port Said

1.4 United Gas Derivatives Company UGDC:

• Client: United Gas Derivatives Company UGDC

• Location : Port Said NGL & Damietta Facilities





2 - Offshore

2.1 Maintenance of platforms AMER 5 & GHARB 4:

Client : GPC Location : Red Sea

• Scope: Fabrication / Repair For (Safety Net Pipes, Hand Rails, Ladders, Gratings, Boat landing & Barge Bumper Dismantling & Erection For (Safety Net Pipes, Heli Deck Safety Net, Hand Rails, Ladders, Gratings, Boat landing & Barge Bumper)

2.2 Supply & install of submarine power cable:

Client : SOPCLocation : Suez

 Scope: Supply a medium voltage submarine power cable including fiber optics cable (total length 4300 m) / Seabed scan and pre survey for the laying path / laying the new cable from onshore to our terminal platform acc.

3 - E & I Work (Electrical & Instrumentation)

3.1 Abu Oir PII DCS EPC:

- Client: Abu Qir Petroleum Co.
- Location: Abu Qir
- Scope: complete upgrade of the existing instruments and control system form Pneumatic to electronic system at Abu Qir PII Platform.

3.2 Kasr OHTL:

- Client: Khalda Petroleum Co.
- Location: Matrouh
- Scope: Engineering, Procurement & Constructing of new (120 KM) 11 KV overhead transmission line networks complete with distribution transformers and wells switching facilities.

3.3 Petrobel Power Plant:

- Client : Belyim Petroleum Co. (PETROBEL)
- Location: Abu Reduis
- Scope: Installation 0f 2 x 10 MW Turbines Generator, Switch Gear and MCC.

4 - EPC Projects (Engineering- Procurement-Construction)

4.1 Laying of 16" Pipeline 71 KM from Dahshour to Fayoum:

• Client : Shell Egypt

• Location : Fayoum

• Scope: assigned take the opportunity to work in this project on year 2001, the scope is limited to engineering, fabrication, laying, commissioning & start-up for 16" underground pipeline for 71 KM between Dahshour to Fayoum cities, In addition to construction, E&I works, mechanical installation, civil works, commissioning for two pressure reduction stations (PRS) & (PRMS).

4.2 Army Civil works:

• Client : Army Force Ministry

• Location : Alexandria & Six of October

• Scope: Construction of various building, Hyper Markets at Alexandria and Six of October.

4.3 KARAMA accommodation facilities:

- Client : Qarun Petroleum Co. / Apachi-Egypt
- Location : Karama Field
- Scope: assigned to take this project as turnkey job, Scope of work including construction of 2 technicians villas, 2 VIP Villa, Mosque, Administration Building, Mess Hall, Clinic, Store, Warehouse, Sewage &Water Tank, Electrical Network.

5 - Static Equipment

5.1 Fabricate & supply (6) sour three phase separators: (Separators Fabrication)

- Client : Qarun Petroleum Company "QPC"
- Location: Western Desert.
- Scope: Fabrication and supply No. of 6 Horizontal three phase separators with Capacity 50,000 BBD

6 - Turbines & Rotating Equipment

6.1 Turbine Overhauling & Maintenance Services:

- Client : GE Oil &Gas (NuovoPignone)
- Location: Abu Rudies, Port Said & IDKU.
- Scope: the provision of overhauling services Gas Turbine, combustion, inspection, hot gas inspection, minor &major inspection, rotor replacement, eddy current and boroscope inspection, dry gas seal replacement, commissioning & alignment.

Job Responsibilities

- Working as a procurement Manager of foreign and local purchasing for all materials (bulk mechanical materials, electrical bulk materials, electronics material, instrument material and all construction materials.
- Plan, organize, direct, manage, and evaluate the purchasing activities and budget of an organization
- Develop and manage the proposal, bidding, and negotiation process while adhering to applicable legal standards and codes of ethical conduct
- Comply with and maintain knowledge of applicable rules, regulations, standards, and best practices
- Ensure all purchasing activities support and strengthen the strategic objectives of the overall organization
- Ensure the adequacy of specifications for purchasing purposes
- Negotiate major purchases, develop blanket or master agreements with suppliers, and engage in all aspects of contract management
- Review supplier financial statements/reports and evaluate overall supplier health (supplier risk assessment)
- Review and assess total supply chain risk and identify opportunities to minimize and eliminate risk
- Confer with management and staff coordinating purchasing activities
- Develop and measure key performance indicators to determine and improve the effectiveness of the purchasing function
- Maintain current technical skills and apply new knowledge to management tasks for the improvement of purchasing activities
- Analyze purchasing related information and evaluate the results to choose the best resolution and alternatives to supply challenges
- Prepare or oversee the preparation of reports and statistics related to the purchasing function for upper management
- Identify, qualify, and select vendors of materials, equipment, products, or services, and conduct overall supplier management
- Evaluate cost and quality of materials, equipment, products, or services
- Manage purchase requisitions/orders
- Review records of materials, equipment, products, or services ordered and received
- Generate and/or review invoices, work orders, consumption reports, and demand forecasts
- Analyze market and delivery systems to assess present and future material availability and alternative sources of supply
- Participate in make or buy decisions
- Interview, select, coach, train, manage, and appraise the performance of associated personnel and mentor select staff
- Develop and maintain constructive and cooperative working relationships with all stakeholders
- Perform and/or direct day to day administrative tasks
- Communicate information to all stakeholders using the appropriate communication method
- Coordinate and expedite the ordering and delivery of material.
- Prepare/ Review Purchase/ Material Requisitions for procurement of equipment/ material for all Projects. Coordinating/ recommending establishment of specifications and standards.
- Follow up approvals of documents/drawings from discipline engineers. Receive purchase order acknowledgment and execution schedules from suppliers. Maintain an expediting file for each

- purchase order, which would be used throughout the project period. Carry out desk as well as field expediting visits to speed up deliveries.
- Review of cost estimates for procurement of material. Plans, reviews and /or undertakes comparative cost analysis of bidder's quotations.
- Reviews & provide comments/ recommendations on Purchase/Material Requisitions (PR/MR), request for quotations (RFQ), Purchase Orders (PO) and contract documents generated by concerned department or other Contractors, through all stages of the project.
- Coordinates and resolves commercial matters with external agencies. Prepare periodic reports on Material Procurement Status.

Key Accountabilities

- Maintain relevant information on assigned projects, such as scope, budget, schedules, etc. and provide analysis and feedback on the Procurement status. Presents to the Management complete overview of the Procurement status highlighting important issues which require management intervention / decisions.
- Develops and ensures proper administrative procedures for Material Procurement.
- Following up evaluation of material tenders/ purchase requisitions and coordinating for placement of Purchase Orders.
- Coordinate for resolution/ response to additional vendor recommended from requested dept. or other contractors.
- Assisting in the inspection of Materials / equipment received for final acceptance.
- Assisting user engineers regarding codes, standards, commercial conditions, specifications, market availability and cost of direct material.
- Suggest resolution to critical issues which can exploit as opportunity/ claims by external agencies.
- Coordinates with legal and commercial departments for clarifications related to procurement / purchase orders and contracts.
- Coordinates with concerned discipline engineers and external agencies on requested change orders.
- Review and Verify the Vendor's invoices. Coordinates with F&A department for invoice Payments.
- Remains available on call after office hours. Performs any other related duties, as assigned
- Working as a Coordinating Engineer logging in new jobs quoted by Sales offices further, dealing
 with all other organization departments for job coordination: Estimating, Engineering, Marketing,
 Production, Transportation, Construction, Quality Control and Finance.
- Reviewing design calculations, approval drawings, erection drawings, bill of materials & materials dispatch notes.
- Reviewing and solving claims regarding design, shops and site problems.
- Initiating conferences (when necessary) between concerned parties (Customer, Reviewing Consultants and Concerned Dept.) to solve any obstacles that may arise during any of the project periods to obtain firm solutions and customer satisfaction.

Knowledge, Skills and Qualifications

- Minimum 14 years' experience in the oil & gas, refining and petrochemical industries. Also in all construction buildings, power plant, etc...
- Ambitious, dynamic, self-motivated excellent communication skills.
- Excellent management and negotiation skills.
- Excellent ability to come across to the client. Also ability to assist and convince him to reach. Proper implementation for the requirements of his business needs.
- Enthusiastic, and committed to development work.
- Excellent ability to cope with demanding workload and deadlines.
- High team work awareness and success in inter-personal relationship.
- Self-training on using different applications.
- Establishing effective operating policies, lean initiatives and processes.
- Ability to manage multiple priorities.
- Regularly achieving cost saving targets.
- Capable of making important and strategic decisions.

- Attention to detail.
- Ability to use sound judgment in decision making areas.
- Ability to handle confidential material judiciously.
- Ability and establish and maintain effective working relationships with employees at all levels.

Academic Qualifications

1997-2002 BSc, in Civil Engineering, Zagazig University, Benha branch at Shoubra, Cairo, Egypt.

Graduate with (good) and (Excellent) in quality control project.

High School, the Prince Fahd Ibn Abd El Aziz Secondary School.

Language

ARABIC: Mother tongue (Read, Speak and Write)

ENGLISH: Very good (Read, Speak and Write)

Computer and Software Skill

• ICDL Certificate (Word - Excel - PowerPoint - Windows - IT - Access - Internet).

• Proficiency in Microsoft systems (Windows XP).

• Good typing speed and Accuracy (English / Arabic).

• Confident in the application of the internet for research purposes and a proficient user of e-mail.

Purchasing Module on ERP Oracle System.

Personal Information

Name : Waleed Salah Tawfeek Shendy Address : Madinaty City - Cairo, Egypt.

Phone : +2 0100 5646 939

E-Mail : eng shendy78@hotmail.com

Position : Procurement / Supply Chain / Purchasing Manager

Date of Birth : 17/10/1978

Place of Birth : Cairo / Egypt

Nationality : Egyptian

Religion : Muslim

Marital Status : Married

Military Status : Terminal Exempted.

Conference and Training Courses Attended

- Supply Chain Certified Professional Certificate American University Egypt, June 17th July 17th, 2012.
- Advanced Project Management Workshop, October 2nd 5th, 2004.
- Foreign Purchasing, Freight and Customs Training Course, November 11th 15th, 2007.
- Domestic & Foreign Purchasing Course including L/G and L/C, September 25th 29th, 2005.
- Program of study in "Presentation Skills", May 9th 10th, 2010.
- Best Employee Performance Certificate, 2007.
- ERP Oracle System on Purchasing Module, September 15th -29nd, 2006.
- Trained in Norway (Vetco Aibel) which the course focused in Supply Chain Management and purchasing Module on SAP System, 2008.

• The 5th international Conference for Building and Construction.

References

Upon Your Request